SERGIO FUENTES

46035 Valencia, Spain • +34 661 277 738 • serfuvaz@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

In my 3 years of experience in sound design I have participated in different game projects, having a pivotal role in the development of an immersive sound identity that enhances gameplay and narrative. As oventured into developing my own games to better understand the implementation within the engine.

With a particular talent for creating compelling soundscapes that resonate with the gaming audience, I am successful at high-quality editing and fast turnarounds thanks to my experience as a freelance music composer.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE. Valencia, Spain - Remote

Sound Designer and Audio Engineer

Mar 2023 - Present

Open to diverse audio-related projects, excelling in tasks ranging from sound design to music production, committed to delivering high-quality assets that exceed client expectations.

- Designed impactful sound for business videos, enhancing social media content to resonate with target audiences and elevate brand presence.
- Meticulously mixed and mastered music for emerging artists, ensuring a professional and polished auditory experience that aligns with artistic visions.

SOULFORGE PRODUCTIONS. Valencia, Spain

Sound Designer and Music Composer

Feb 2021 - Mar 2023

Design and implement sounds with Unreal Engine, compose music for the development of different video game prototypes as a freelancer for the Soulforge developer collective.

- Created original music and sounds for a prospective AAA game set on Brandon Sanderson's epic universe
 of Mistborn, presented on a dedicated website as Mistborn: Ashes Project.
- Designed weapons, character and enemies audio assets for a roguelike action game inspired by 80's sci-fi
 B-movies. Also composed an original soundtrack of six complete themes.
- Participated in game design meetings with the team, bringing creative ideas from my audio experience that became part of the game pitch.

VOICEMOD Ltd. Valencia, Spain

Music Composer

Dec 2020 - Jan 2023

Arrange and produce video game-themed music on demand as a freelancer, participating as reinforcement to complete the catalogue of certain products within two weeks of their publication, being required sporadically during the specified dates.

- Delivered two complete songs inspired by DOOM and Cyberpunk 2077 that helped to create an immersive experience for Voicemod's millions of users.
- Acomplished composition, mixing, and mastering of two EDM songs for Voicemod Text to Song, as well as melody design for AI: "Lazer Beam" and "Move Your Body".
- Provided advice and delivered five proposals for an advertising campaign that helped bring Voicemod's product to a younger target.

EDUCATION

ADECCO. Valencia, Spain

260 hours - 2023

Videogame Programming, 3D Design & Virtual Reality

UNIVERSITY OF BARCELONA. Barcelona, Spain Music For Videogames Bootcamp By ENTI 46 hours - 2021